<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: css | Madole's Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://madole.github.io/blog/categories/css/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://madole.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-30T12:01:50+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://madole.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew McDowell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compass - SASS - Boostrap SASS]]></title>
    <link href="http://madole.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/compass-sass/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T21:25:58+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://madole.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/compass-sass</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About a month ago, we decided to use SASS on our side project because we wanted to learn some of the new ways to
pre-process CSS. I have used LESS before (which is a Node.js preprocessor) in a work project so it makes sense
to use something different for this learning experience. We then boiled down the choices to just two, SASS or Stylus.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>
We chose SASS and I got down to doing some research. I learned it was built on Ruby, I also learned that a lot of people
who use SASS also use Compass as it provides a bunch of mixins that are pretty handy when you come to writing
your SASS. We wanted to use Bootstrap but at that point we weren&rsquo;t aware of the Bootstrap-SASS port, and it was only officially
written in CSS and LESS.</p>

<p>I had looked into using SASS alongside the CSS version of Bootstrap but then one day when browsing GitHub, I came
across the Bootstrap-SASS official port.
Another layer of complexity to this learning experience but sure where&rsquo;s the fun if you&rsquo;re not jumping in at the deep end.</p>

<p>I decided that as I was researching how to get set up with Compass, SASS and Bootstrap SASS for the first time,
I would document it in a presentation form. This as a) for me because my memory is terrible and b) for my team mates
so they wouldn&rsquo;t have to make the mistakes I did.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve included this presentation in a PDF format below so take a look, have a play about and leave me some feedback so
I can make this as useful as possible for others just starting out with these tools too</p>

<p><a href="/assets/pdfs/compass-sass-getting-started.pdf">Compass SASS &ndash; Get started with the awesome</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
